## ARAVINDA KETIPEARACHCHI

Clarkesville, GA 30523 (320) 282-7916 | aravinda.ketipe@gmail.com

Cyber Security student with four semesters of mechanical engineering education; utilizing skills from both areas of study to provide efficient IT services and maintain network and information security. High levels of experience in adaptability, teamwork, and communication.

# **EDUCATION**

St. Cloud State University, St. Cloud, MN

• Degree: Bachelor of Science in Cyber Security, Spring 2024

#### **SKILLS**

- Networking Protocols and Concepts, DNS, DHCP, VLAN,
- Operating Systems: MacOS, MS Windows, Windows Servers, and Kali Linux
- Scripting: Moderate skills in PowerShell, Python, Bash, Arduino, VScode
- Expert skills in System Administration, IT Security, Database systems, Defense Security, Project Management, Customer Service
- Moderate: Computer Forensics, Applied Cryptography, Agile methodologies, Firewall configs(Palo Alto)
- Expertise on MS Office Package, Adobe Premier Pro, Lightroom and Photoshop,

# **Projects & Activities**

- Hotel Room Management Database
- o Designed a room reservation system to a mid-level hotel using MySQL.
- o Used MySQL Workbench and server to create tables and normalizations.
- CCDC(Collegiate Cyber Defense Competition) 2024
- o Palo Alto 11: Configured and secured the team Network environment.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FACILITIES MANAGEMENT,

(June 2019-Jan 2020), (April 2020- Present)

St. Cloud State University - Saint Cloud, MN.

Worked as a cross-functioning student worker in different departments.

- Grounds and Roads maintenance Worker (June 2019-Present)
- o Maintain university premises by cutting grass, trimming trees, and overseeing lawn care.
- o Supervise and train temporary student workers.
- Basic Architectural Graphic Technician (Sept 2020-May2021)
- o Updated and validated building maps, safety procedures, and equipment information.
- Warehouse and Receiving and Front Desk Assistant (June 2019 Jan 2020)
- o Acted as a central point of contact, handling phone inquiries, work order assignments, and customer service.

#### CO-OP MECHANICAL ENGINEERING INTERN,

(Feb. 2020- Mar. 2020)

#### Chart Industries - New Prague, MN.

- Implemented 99.99% precise methods for distance calculation in 3D CAD.
- Cost reduction initiative resulting in 10% reduction in parts cost for high usage vessels.
- Optimized MathCad calculations, reducing the number of calculations required to 10%.
- Reviewed and examined existing Stock-Keeping Units for Product Line Simplification (PLS).

#### OFFICE ASSISTANT.

## College of Education Dean's Office - St. Cloud State University, St. Cloud, MN

(Sept. 2017- May 2021)

- Coordinate visitor access and assist with daily tasks, prioritizing security, and data protection.
- support operational efficiency, including managing sensitive information.
- Create and edit spreadsheets, applying complex formulas for data analysis and reporting.

# **REFERENCES**

Barron Nixon

• Building Maintenance Supervisor (320) 293-6840

Halyn Mathers

• Former IT Engineer (320) 221-4968

Kavinga Batuvita

• Network Security Engineer (320) 266-7378

Dayan Meemaduma

Mechanical Engineer (507) 475-4478

barron.nixon@stcloudstate.edu

HAMathers@outlook.com

kavinganiroshan14@gmail.com

dmeemaduma@hotmail.com